**Updated on February 18, 2023.**

### **In brief**

We respect your privacy and this document explains the privacy rules applicable to all information collected or submitted when you access, install or use the Red Shield VPN services (hereinafter – ‘**Services’**).

By visiting our websites or applications, by submitting your personal data to us, and by accessing, installing and/or using Services, **you confirm** that you have read this Privacy Policy, agree to be bound by this Privacy Policy and give us consent for data processing.

**If you disagree** with the rules of this Privacy Policy, please **do not use the Services**.

### **Processing of your data**

Red Shield VPN processes user data to a **limited scope** – for provision of the Services, processing payments for the Services, support implementation, as well as the functioning of our websites and mobile applications. We process the following basic information:

* **Name**. This is necessary to establish a Red Shield VPN account.
    
* **Email address.** We use your email address to: i) establish a Red Shield VPN account and retrieve a lost password; ii) send you important updates and announcements related to your use of our Services; iii) respond to your requests or inquiries; iv) send you offers, surveys and other marketing content; v) send emails related to payment transactions.
    
* **Payment data** (when using paid Services). This information is necessary to collect payments for our Services. In addition to the traditional payment methods, such as credit cards, users can buy our Service with cryptocurrency. Our payment processing partners process basic billing information for payment processing and refund requests. We also process some of the same payment information ourselves in cases of recurring payments. You can disable recurring payments in your dashboard ([my.redshieldvpn.com](https://my.redshieldvpn.com/)) in the "Profile" section.
    
    * Please note that payments from certain countries are processed by third parties. The list of such countries is provided below and is subject to update:
        
        * Russia – Private Networks LP, Suite 1 4 Queen Street, Edinburgh, United Kingdom, EH2 1JE, Reg. No. SL030265.
            
* **Country details.** When providing your payment details, we ask our users to provide the country where they are registered, have a permanent address or usually live. This information is necessary for VAT calculation purposes.
    
* **Communication optimization data.** We use various tools to help us optimize our emailing campaigns. These tools may track events you perform with an email, such as open and unsubscribe. We may also be able to see the user device’s operating system in order to optimize push notifications.
    
* **Chat-bot.** If you contact us via our chat-bot on our website, we will be able to see your contact information. This additional information is necessary for our support to determine the user's country and to see if the user is connected to our servers or not.
    
* **Access logs.** As most websites on the internet, our website collects access logs to operate our services and ensure their secure, reliable, and robust performance. This information is also essential for fighting against DDoS attacks, scanning and similar hacking attempts.
    
* **Cookies.** Cookies, web beacons, pixels and other similar technologies are usually small text or image files that are placed on your device when you visit our website. Some cookies are essential for our website to operate smoothly; others are used to improve website functionality or analyze aggregated usage statistics to improve website performance. We also use affiliate cookies to identify the customers referred to the website by our partners so that we can grant the referrers their commission and to measure the effectiveness of their advertising campaigns and/or to personalize the advertising content that you see on websites that you visit. We have no control over these cookies. You can choose to disable cookies through your individual browser options. To know more detailed information about cookie management with specific web browsers, it can be found at the browsers' respective websites.
    
* **Diagnostic data.** We analyze your IP address, but delete it immediately (do not save) to optimize network speeds, to identify problems and areas for improvement.
    
* **Legal requirements.** Pursuant to statutory requirements we might be obliged to process other personal information to protect our legitimate interests and legal rights. Personal information is being stored for a period established by the applicable law. User activities outside of the Red Shield VPN website are not tracked nor do we track the browsing activities of users who are logged to the Services.

### **Sharing your personal data**

We do not sell, rent or share your personal information with third parties except as described in this Privacy Policy.

**Service providers.** We use third-party service providers to help us with various operations, such as payment processing, email automation, website and app diagnostics, analytics and other. As a result, some of these providers may process personal information. Our service providers receive the information they absolutely need in order to perform their functions.

Sometimes our service providers will be independent controllers of your data. Their terms and conditions and privacy policies will apply to such relationships. 

Your personal information may be processed in any country where we have facilities or in which we engage service providers. When you use our Services, you acknowledge and permit the transfer of your personal information outside of the country where you reside.

**Business Transfers.** To any acquiring company if, at any point, we are acquired or merged with another company.

**Legal.** We disclose personal information to law enforcement authorities or courts of competent jurisdiction when we are asked and legally obliged to do so. Any official request for user data should follow an appropriate legal process to be recognized by the applicable law. Contact information for government authorities: _Private Network Labs LLC, 512 Lucerne Ave., Suite 169, Lake Worth, FL 33460, USA_.

### **Choices related to your data**

If you’d like to edit your profile information, delete your account or data, or request to provide you with a copy of your personal information, please contact our support team – [**contact@redshieldvpn.com**](mailto:contact@redshieldvpn.com).  Please note that you may need to pass through a couple of account verification steps so that we can verify you are the owner of the account. We will respond to all requests in a timely manner.

If you wish **to unsubscribe** from our communication, you can opt out at any time.

Some browsers have incorporated a “do-not-track” feature that can send a signal to the websites you visit, indicating you do not wish to be tracked. Currently, our systems do not recognize browser “do-not-track” requests.

**If you disagree** with the processing of your data by Red Shield VPN, **please do not use our Services**. You can request us to discontinue processing your personal data, in which case your data will be processed only as much as is necessary to effect the discontinuation of your use of the Services, or finalizing other Red Shield VPN’s legal relationship with you.

If you wish to use the Services again, you will have to accept and agree to this Privacy Policy anew.

### **Data security**

We take data security very seriously and take all steps reasonably necessary to secure your data (whether technical, physical, or administrative). However, no company can guarantee the absolute security of internet communications. By using the Services, you expressly acknowledge that we cannot guarantee the security of any data provided to or received by us through the Services and that any information received from you through the website or our Services is provided at your own responsibility.

### **Children’s Privacy**

The Services are not intended for anyone **under the age of 18**. Such users are expressly prohibited from submitting any of their information to us, and from using portions of the Services for which registration is required. If any information is submitted by such users, it will not be collected or retained.

If you are either a parent or guardian and believe that your underage child has provided personal information to us, please contact us immediately at [**contact@redshieldvpn.com**](mailto:contact@redshieldvpn.com) so that we can delete the child’s information.

**General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR)**
---------------------------------------------

We are a Data Controller of your information.

Private Network Labs LLC legal basis for collecting and using the personal information described in this Privacy Policy depends on the personal information we collect and the specific context in which we collect the information:

* Private Network Labs LLC needs to perform a contract with you;
    
* You have given Private Network Labs LLC permission to do so;
    
* Processing your personal information is in Private Network Labs LLC legitimate interests;
    
* Private Network Labs LLC needs to comply with the law.

Private Network Labs LLC will retain your personal information only for as long as is necessary with respect to applicable law. We will retain and use your information to the extent necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our policies. 

If you are a resident of the European Economic Area (EEA), you have certain data protection rights. You can download your Personal Information and delete the account in your dashboard ([my.redshieldvpn.com](https://my.redshieldvpn.com/)) in the "Profile" section. If you wish to be informed what Personal Information we hold about you and if you want it to be removed from our systems, please contact us.

In certain circumstances, you have the following data protection rights:

* The right to access, update or to delete the information we have on you;
    
* The right of rectification;
    
* The right to object;
    
* The right of restriction;
    
* The right to data portability;
    
* The right to withdraw consent.

### **Other Terms**

The Privacy Policy is governed by and shall be construed in accordance with the laws provided in our Terms of Services. This policy is not applicable to any information collected offline or via channels other than this website or mobile application.

To ensure the security of personal data, Red Shield VPN employs various administrative, technical and physical security measures; however, it is your responsibility to exercise caution and reason when using the Services. You will be personally responsible if such action violates any third party’s privacy or any other rights, or any applicable law. Under no circumstances is Red Shield VPN liable for the consequences of your unlawful activities, your willful and negligent activities that violate applicable laws or third-party rights, and any circumstances that may not have been reasonably controlled or foreseen.

Our website may include links to other websites whose privacy practices may be different from ours. The Privacy Policy does not apply to them.  If you submit personal information to any of those sites, your information is governed by their privacy policies. We encourage you to carefully read the privacy policy of any website you visit.

This Privacy Policy may be modified and updated at any time, at our sole discretion, for any or no reason, and without liability, as indicated below. The date of the most current wording of the Privacy Policy is indicated at the top of the text. We ask all users to ensure that they are familiar with the most current wording of the Privacy Policy. The amendment of the Privacy Policy may be communicated to you by sending an email and/or by publishing the updated Privacy Policy on this website. Updates of the Privacy Policy come into force as of the moment when they are published.

You may not assign or transfer your rights or obligations under this Privacy Policy to any third party.

### **How to Contact Us**

If you have any questions regarding this Privacy Policy or would like further information on our privacy practices, we encourage you to email us at [**contact@redshieldvpn.com**](mailto:contact@redshieldvpn.com).
